http://ssom.luc.edu/privacy-policy/

Stritch School of Medicine  >  Content   >  Privacy Policy
Stritch School of Medicine (SSOM) is committed to excellence in patient care and the education of health professionals. We believe that thoughtful stewardship, learning and constant reflection on experience improve all we do as we strive to provide the highest quality healthcare. That quality of care is extended to our web sites and the contents provided therein.
SSOM is very interested in the privacy and safety of our patients and visitors to our web sites. This privacy policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard personal information which you may provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our sites. This statement will be continuously assessed against new technologies, business practices and our patients' and visitors' needs.
This privacy policy does not apply to the Loyola University Medical Education Network website (LUMEN). When visiting LUMEN at www.lumen.luc.edu/lumen, please review the posted policies as to the use of that site.
We will post general notices of changes to this policy, but individual notice of changes to web site visitors will not be provided. Please check back periodically and review this privacy policy to ensure that you still agree with its terms. You will be bound by any subsequent changes in the privacy policy, even if you do not become aware of such changes.
What You Should Know About Information We Send to YouPlease remember that information provided by SSOM, in the absence of a visit with a health-care professional, must be considered as an educational service only. The information sent through e-mail should not be relied upon as a medical consultation. Information we send you by e-mail is not designed to replace your physician's independent judgment about the appropriateness or risks of a procedure for a given patient. We will do our best to provide you with information that will help you make your own health-care decisions. While we are very interested in providing relevant personal health-care information to patients and/or their physicians, we will not make such information available online until we are confident that the information is secure.
How We May Use Personal Information You Choose to Provide UsSSOM does not obtain personal information about you when you visit our site, unless you provide us that information voluntarily. Our web sites contain forms through which users may request information or supply feedback to us. In some cases, telephone numbers or return addresses may be required so that we can supply the requested information to you. Please note that our forms are NOT encrypted unless otherwise noted. Therefore, people who are actively attempting to intercept web transmissions may be able to read information you send to us. However, we have installed a number of security measures to protect the confidentiality of your personal information. We have a firewall to prevent unauthorized access to our systems. Once the information is sent to our sites, it is kept on a separate database not available to users on the Internet and protected to the fullest extent reasonably possible.
We will not provide, sell or distribute any personal information received from visitors on web forms or e-mail to any outside organization. However, we may disclose information when legally compelled to do so.
Why We Track Where You Go on Our Web SitesIn order to understand how our web site is being used, we do typical web traffic analyses through which we track which pages are visited and in what order, where users come from and how long users spend on our sites. We never associate such information with the specific identities of users or other personally identifiable information.
This information is used in the aggregate to help us improve our sites and make it more useful to you. We do disclose such aggregate information that does not identify individuals to partners, advertisers and other third parties.
What Are Cookies and How Do We Use Information Collected from Them?SSOM web sites utilize a standard technology called "cookies" and web server logs to collect information about how our web sites are used. A "cookie" is a small line of text that is stored with your web browser when you visit a cookie-enabled web site. The text may contain an identification code or user preferences. Your browser has options that allow you to control whether the browser accepts cookies, rejects cookies or notifies you each time a cookie is sent to you.
Should any SSOM page utilize cookies, you will see a pop-up disclaimer box that will read: "This page makes use of special programming designed to collect and monitor your personal browsing habits. By clicking the following box you acknowledge your acceptance of this information." The box will also explain what information is being collected and how it will be used. You may choose to accept or decline cookies. If you choose to decline cookies, you may still access the information contained on this site.
Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by visitors to our web sites as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our web sites and evaluate our web site visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual e-mail address or any personally identifying information about you.
The Use and Security of E-mail The comments form, which is submitted to the Director of Interactive Marketing Division, is intended for comments relating to the SSOM web sites and their design and functionality. The information submitted is reviewed by the webmaster and by the SSOM web site steering committee. The comments are used to determine areas of the SSOM web sites that need improvement or correction, or to determine new content that should be added. When submitting an e-mail comment to the webmaster, users are asked to provide their name, e-mail address and organization/institution. This information is voluntary and is not required to submit a comment.
If you ask us a question or would like a response to a comment, the inclusion of an accurate, viable e-mail address is necessary in order for us to respond. On some forms, where you may be asked to provide your e-mail address, we may tell you that we will add your name to a health information and distribution list unless you ask us not to do so. These forms will contain an opt-out check box labeled "please do not sent me any health information." We will occasionally send health information or other notices regarding important changes to our web sites and new services which we think valuable to those people who do not opt-out. In addition to or in place of checking the opt-out check box, you may contact the SSOM webmaster at luhswebmaster@lumc.edu and indicate your desire not to receive any health information or other unsolicited e-mails from SSOM.
Please be aware that normal e-mail is not encrypted. Active snoopers may be able to read e-mail that we send you or that you send us. If you ask us a question and supply your e-mail address, you are authorizing us to respond to you with an unencrypted e-mail message that may contain private information about you or your question. While we are responsible for the privacy of messages that we store on the network, we cannot be responsible for the privacy of those messages once we have transmitted them to you or to your e-mail provider.
Children's Privacy Naturally, the safety of children is very important to us. While some sections of the SSOM web site are designed for use by children under the age of 13, SSOM does not request, seek or intentionally collect personal information from children under the age of 13. Should a child under the age of 13 wish to submit a comment or send an e-mail to SSOM without expectation of a response, that child should not fill in any information on the comment form except the comment box. Children under the age of 13 who submit such e-mails or comments should not include their e-mail address, name or other personal information. In the event that SSOM has actual knowledge that it has received an e-mail from a child under the age of 13 that contains personal information provided solely so that SSOM may respond to the e-mail, such information will be discarded 60 days after it is received. In accordance with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act, SSOM will make reasonable efforts to obtain parental consent via an original e-mail submission in advance of any child under the age of 13 submitting a comment that includes personal information before it will be stored for more than 60 days.
Any personal information gathered from the children's area of SSOM web sites (Ronald McDonald Children's Hospital of Loyola University Medical Center, rmch.lumc.edu) either before or after parental consent is obtained, is not disclosed to any third-parties nor is that information used to generate promotions or send unsolicited e-mails to children.
Parents can review any personal information sent by their child to SSOM, ask to have it deleted, or refuse to allow any further collection or use of the child's information by sending an e-mail requesting same to the SSOM webmaster at luhswebmaster@lumc.edu.
Links to Other Web SitesIn order to provide visitors with greater value, SSOM may provide links to various third-party web sites. We are not responsible for the practices employed by web sites linked to or from our web sites nor the information or content contained therein.
Please remember that when you use a link to go from SSOM web sites to another web site, our privacy policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other web site, including web sites that have a link on our web site, is subject to that web site's own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding. These destination links are provided only for your convenience, and as such, you access them at your own risk.
Employee Access, Training and ExpectationsAll SSOM employees involved in web development or who otherwise access the data collected on the web sites have been fully educated about the SSOM privacy policy, terms and conditions of use and disclaimer. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information, and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes and transactions. All said employees must abide by our privacy policy, and those who violate said policies are subject to disciplinary action, up to and including termination.
Threaded Discussions/Web Board SSOM provides specified users with the opportunity to utilize threaded of discussion boards, also known as Web Board. Please remember that information that you voluntarily disclose in these areas becomes public information that can be collected and used by others. If you post personal information on the Web Board that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. As such, you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information on the Web Board. For further terms and conditions regarding the use of the SSOM threaded discussion boards, please see the Threaded Discussion Guidelines.
Contacting the Web Site If you have any questions about this privacy policy, the practices of the SSOM web sites, or your interaction with the SSOM web sites, contact:
Manager, Web DevelopmentStritch School of Medicine2160 South First AvenueBuilding 120-420Maywood, IL 60153gklitz@lumc.edu
AdmissionEducationResearchDepartments & PeopleVisitAbout Us
